<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">

<!-- Business wire confirmation number: 1080879c -->

<PressRelease>

<FileBase>2002-05-21-eldred-brief</FileBase>

  <Copyright years="2002">Free Software Foundation, Inc.</Copyright>

  <License>
      Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is
      permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
  </License>

<Title>Free Software Foundation Files Brief Amicus Curiae in Eldred v. Aschroft Supreme Court Case</Title>

  <ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>
  
  <Location>Boston, Massachusetts, USA</Location>

  <Date>Tuesday, May 21, 2002</Date>

  <KeyWordList>
    <KeyWord value="GNU"/>
    <KeyWord value="FSF"/>
    <KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
    <KeyWord value="Linux"/>
    <KeyWord value="freedom"/>
    <KeyWord value="software"/>
    <KeyWord value="power"/>
    <KeyWord value="rights"/>
    <KeyWord value="copyrigth"/>
    <KeyWord value="extension"/>
    <KeyWord value="opinion"/>
    <KeyWord value="edlred"/>
    <KeyWord value="ashcroft"/>
    <KeyWord value="mickey mouse"/>
    <KeyWord value="law"/>
    <KeyWord value="disney"/>
    <KeyWord value="sonny bono"/>
    <KeyWord value="retroactive"/>
    <KeyWord value="perpetual"/>
  </KeyWordList>

  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
    <Name>Bradley M. Kuhn</Name>
    <Email>pr@fsf.org</Email>
    <Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsf.org/</URL>
  </Contact>

<Body>
   <Para>
    Yesterday, the Free Software Foundation (FSF) filed a Brief Amicus
    Curiae in the pending Supreme Court case, Eldred v. Aschroft.  The
    future of copyright law in the digital age is at issue in this case.
    For decades, the US Congress has been retroactively extending
    copyright protection, directly harming the public good by withholding
    material from the public domain.  FSF strongly supports the rights of
    the public to benefit from useful intellectual works.</Para>
   <Para>
    In our brief, Eben Moglen, FSF Board Member and General Counsel,
     wrote: "The constitutional importance of the 'limited Times'
     restriction cannot be vitiated ... by affording Congress the
     opportunity to create perpetuities on the installment plan, any more
     than Congress can eliminate the constitutional requirement of
     originality".  He continues: "To turn the system of free expression
     into a series of private fiefdoms for the benefit of monopolists ...
     is forbidden to Congress by the plain wording of the Copyright Clause
     and by the First Amendment".
   </Para>
   <Para>
    While nearly all of the Free Software code base at the core of the
    popular GNU/Linux operating system is copyrighted--much of it
    protected by FSF's GNU General Public License (GPL)--FSF promotes a
    healthy and vibrant public domain.  Copyright is a government-granted,
    limited time, monopolistic control that has run amok.  FSF filed this
    amicus brief to stand with those who fight for the public's freedom to
    build on the intellectual works of the past.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    The full brief is 
    available at
    <URL>http://www.fsf.org/philosophy/eldred-amicus.html</URL>.
   </Para>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation">
<Para>
The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to promoting
computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute
computer programs.  FSF promotes the development and use of free (as
in freedom) software--particularly the GNU operating system and its
GNU/Linux variants--and free documentation for free software.  FSF
also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and political issues of
freedom in the use of software.  Their web site, located at
<URL>http://www.gnu.org</URL>, is an important source of information about
GNU/Linux.  They are headquartered in Boston, MA, USA.
</Para>
</About>

<BoilerPlateFooter/>
</Body>    

</PressRelease>

<!--  LocalWords:  Amicus amicus public's
 -->
