<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">

<!-- Business wire confirmation number: NONE YET -->

<PressRelease>

<FileBase>2002-09-03-bayonne</FileBase>

  <Copyright years="2002">Free Software Foundation, Inc.</Copyright>

  <License>
      Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is
      permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
  </License>

<Title>GNU Bayonne 1.0 Released; GNU Telephony Server gives software
           freedom to businesses, large enterprises and commercial
           telephone carriers
</Title>

  <ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>
  
  <Location>Bayonne, NJ, USA</Location>

  <Date>Tuesday, September 3, 2002</Date>

  <KeyWordList>
    <KeyWord value="GNU"/>
    <KeyWord value="FSF"/>
    <KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
    <KeyWord value="Linux"/>
    <KeyWord value="freedom"/>
    <KeyWord value="software"/>
    <KeyWord value="rights"/>
    <KeyWord value="telephony"/>
    <KeyWord value="telephone"/>
    <KeyWord value="phone"/>
    <KeyWord value="network"/>
    <KeyWord value="bayonne"/>
    <KeyWord value="enterprise"/>
    <KeyWord value="voice"/>
    <KeyWord value="voicemail"/>
    <KeyWord value="scripting"/>
    <KeyWord value="GPL"/>
    <KeyWord value="PRI"/>
    <KeyWord value="circuit"/>
  </KeyWordList>

  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
    <Name>David Sugar</Name>
    <Email>sugar@gnu.org</Email>
    <Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsf.org/</URL>
  </Contact>

<Body>
   <Para>After two years of active development, the GNU project has
     released GNU Bayonne, Version 1.0.  GNU Bayonne, licensed freely
     under the GNU General Public License (GPL), allows small businesses,
     large enterprises, and commercial telephone carriers to create,
     deploy, and manage their own web-integrated telephony voice response
     solutions.  By making use of existing computer telephony commercially
     available for GNU/Linux, Bayonne can support all capacities -- from a
     single analog phone circuit to multiple PRI spans.</Para>

  <Para>As part of GNU Enterprise (GNUe), Bayonne 1.0 joins the ranks of a
     host of enterprise-level software for the popular GNU/Linux operating
     system.  "In this 1.0 release, we have established a Free Software
     platform for the delivery of quality telephony services everywhere",
     said David Sugar, GNU Bayonne project leader.  "We are committed to
     establishing Free Software as the primary means to advance
     telecommunications services as part of enterprise software
     infrastructure that respects software freedom, and supports both
     current and next generation telephone networks".</Para>

  <Para>GNU Bayonne is a free software project and has been developed by
     volunteers around the world.  These volunteers cooperate with other
     Free Software development groups, including those working on Carrier
     Grade extensions for the kernel named Linux.  Meanwhile, a number of
     organizations and individuals have contributed resources and time to
     create GNU Bayonne 1.0.  The Free Software Foundation and the GNU
     project have provided technical, infrastructure, and organizational
     support for GNU Bayonne development.  The Open Source Telecom
     Corporation has provided commercial sponsorship of GNU Bayonne
     development.</Para>

  <Para>GNU Bayonne can be obtained in source code form directly from
     <URL>ftp://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/bayonne/</URL>.  It include in many popular
     GNU/Linux and FreeBSD distributions, including the Official Debian
     GNU/Linux system.  </Para>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation">
<Para>
The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to promoting
computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute
computer programs.  FSF promotes the development and use of free (as
in freedom) software--particularly the GNU operating system and its
GNU/Linux variants--and free documentation for free software.  FSF
also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and political issues of
freedom in the use of software.  Their web site, located at
<URL>http://www.gnu.org</URL>, is an important source of information about
GNU/Linux.  They are headquartered in Boston, MA, USA.
</Para>
</About>

<About topic="GNU Enterprise">
<Para>
GNUe aims to provide a suite of tools and applications for solving the
specific needs of the enterprise.  GNUe will handle the needs of any size
business, including applications for human resources, accounting, customer
relationship management, project management, supply chain and e-commerce.
GNUe is a free software project developed by volunteer software developers
worldwide.  The website of GNU Enterprise is
<URL>http://www.gnu.org/projects/gnue/</URL>.
</Para>

</About>

<About topic="OST">
   <Para>
    OST is a privately held provider of telecommunications hardware,
     software, and services.  OST strives to develop of truly open
     telecommunications systems and technologies.  OST's goal is to
     generate value, opportunity, and peace of mind for its customers and
     investors.
    </Para>
  </About>
<BoilerPlateFooter/>
</Body>    

</PressRelease>

<!--  LocalWords:  Amicus amicus public's
 -->
