<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">

<PressRelease>

  <FileBase>2002-02-16-FSF-Award</FileBase>

  <Copyright years="2002">Free Software Foundation Free Software
      Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110, USA
  </Copyright>

  <License>
      Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is
      permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
  </License>

  <Title>Guido van Rossum Awarded the Free Software Foundation Award for
  the Advancement of Free Software</Title>

  <ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>

  <Location>Brussels, Belgium</Location>
  <Date>Saturday, February 16, 2002</Date>

  <Description>
  </Description>

  <KeyWordList>
    <KeyWord value="GNU"/>
    <KeyWord value="FSF"/>
    <KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
    <KeyWord value="Linux"/>
    <KeyWord value="award"/>
    <KeyWord value="advancement"/>
    <KeyWord value="freedom"/>
    <KeyWord value="software"/>
    <KeyWord value="Guido"/>
    <KeyWord value="van Rossum"/>
  </KeyWordList>

  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
    <Name>Bradley M. Kuhn</Name>
    <Email>pr@gnu.org</Email>
    <Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsf.org</URL>
  </Contact>
  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation Europe</Organization>
    <Name>Georg C. F. Greve</Name>
    <Email>greve@gnu.org</Email>
    <Phone>+49-40-23809080</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsfe.org</URL>
  </Contact>

<Body>
   <Para>
    The Free Software Foundation (FSF) bestowed today its fourth annual
     FSF Award for the Advancement of Free Software.  FSF President and
     founder, Richard Stallman, presented the award to Guido van Rossum
     for inventing and implementing as Free Software the Python
     programming language.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    The award ceremony was hosted at the Free and Open Source Software
     Developers' Meeting (FOSDEM) in collaboration with the Free Software
     Foundation Europe.
     </Para>
   <Para>
    A committee of Free Software pioneers and leaders selected the winner
     and two other finalists from the scores of mostly volunteer
     programmers worldwide who dedicate their time to advancing Free
     Software.  The selection committee included: Miguel de Icaza, Ian
     Murdock, Eric Raymond, Peter Salus, Vernor Vinge, and Larry Wall.
     Prior to committee deliberations, a two month open nominations
     process decided the list from which the committee chose these
     finalists.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    Guido van Rossum was chosen from three finalists for the award.  The
     other finalists were L. Peter Deutsch, for his work on GNU
     Ghostscript, the popular Postscript emulation program for GNU/Linux,
     and Andrew Tridgell, for his work on Samba, a Microsoft Windows
     network file system emulation program.
    </Para>
   <Para>
    This was the fourth award of this kind.  The prior winners were Larry
    Wall, Miguel de Icaza, and Brian Paul.
    </Para>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation Europe">

<Para>
     The Free Software Foundation Europe (FSF Europe) is a charitable
      non-governmental organization dedicated to all aspects of Free
      Software in Europe. Access to software determines who may
      participate in a digital society. Therefore the freedoms to use,
      copy, modify and redistribute software - as described in the Free
      Software definition - allow equal participation in the information
      age. Creating awareness for these issues, securing Free Software
      politically and legally, and giving people freedom by supporting
      development of Free Software are central issues of the FSF Europe,
      which was founded in 2001 as the European sister organization of the
      Free Software Foundation in the United States.
</Para>
<Para>
     More information about the FSF Europe can be found at
      <URL>http://www.fsfe.org/</URL>.
</Para>
</About>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation">
<Para>
The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to promoting
computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute
computer programs.  The FSF promotes the development and use of free (as
in freedom) software---particularly the GNU operating system and its
GNU/Linux variants---and free documentation for free software.  The FSF
also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and political issues of
freedom in the use of software.  Their web site, located at
<URL>http://www.gnu.org</URL>, is an important source of information about
GNU/Linux.  They are headquartered in Boston, MA, USA.
</Para>
  </About>

<About topic="GNU/Linux">
<Para>
  GNU/Linux is the integrated combination of the GNU operating system with
  the kernel, Linux, written by Linus Torvalds in 1991.  The various
  versions of GNU/Linux have an estimated 20 million users.
</Para>
<Para>
  Some people call the GNU/Linux system "Linux", but this misnomer leads to
  confusion (people cannot tell whether you mean the whole system or the
  kernel, one part), and spreads an inaccurate picture of how, when and
  where the system was developed.  Making a consistent distinction between
  GNU/Linux, the whole operating system, and Linux, the kernel, is the best
  way to clear up the confusion.  See
  <URL>http://www.gnu.org/gnu/linux-and-gnu.html</URL> for more
  explanation.
</Para>
</About>
</Body>

   <BoilerPlateFooter/>
</PressRelease>
<!--  LocalWords:  PressRelease FileBase Rossum ReleaseTime KeyWordList KeyWord
 -->
<!--  LocalWords:  FOSDEM Icaza Salus Vinge Ghostscript Tridgell Torvalds
 -->
<!--  LocalWords:  BoilerPlateFooter
 -->
