<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">

<PressRelease>

  <FileBase>2002-03-01-pi-MySQL</FileBase>

  <Copyright years="2002">Free Software Foundation Free Software
      Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110, USA
  </Copyright>

  <License>
      Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is
      permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
  </License>

  <Title>Judge Saris defers GNU GPL Questions for Trial in MySQL
  vs. Progress Software</Title>

  <ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>
  
  <Location>Boston, Massachusetts, USA</Location>
  <Date>Friday, March, 1, 2002</Date>

  <Description>
  </Description>

  <KeyWordList>
    <KeyWord value="GNU"/>
    <KeyWord value="FSF"/>
    <KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
    <KeyWord value="Linux"/>
    <KeyWord value="GPL"/>
    <KeyWord value="legal"/>
    <KeyWord value="copyright"/>
    <KeyWord value="enforcement"/>
    <KeyWord value="Progress"/>
    <KeyWord value="Nusphere"/>
    <KeyWord value="MySQL"/>
    <KeyWord value="general"/>
    <KeyWord value="public"/>
    <KeyWord value="license"/>
  </KeyWordList>

  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
    <Name>Bradley M. Kuhn </Name>
    <Email>pr@fsf.org</Email>
    <Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsf.org/</URL>
  </Contact>

<Body>

   <Para>
     In a decision handed down today in Boston, US District Judge Patti
     B. Saris ruled on the preliminary injunction motion in MySQL AB
     vs. Progress Software Corp.  On the trademark dispute, on which the
     Free Software Foundation (FSF) takes no position, she has ruled that
     Progress Software is enjoined from marketing products under the MySQL
     trademarks until trial.
    </Para>
    <Para>
     On the matter of Progress' distribution rights under GNU GPL, she has
     not granted an injunction.  In the public hearing this week, Judge
     Saris made clear that she sees the GNU GPL to be an enforceable and
     binding license, but that as long as Progress Software appears to be
     presently in compliance with the GNU GPL, there is probably no
     irreparable harm being caused to MySQL AB.  Since Progress did
     previously distribute in violation of the GNU GPL and thus did harm
     MySQL AB and the Free Software community, the FSF expects MySQL to
     prevail at trial on these claims.  The Court recognizes in today's
     order that MySQL "seems to have the better argument".
   </Para>
   <Para>
     The Court fully recognized the need for expert testimony at trial
     about the GNU GPL and the technical facts at hand, particularly as to
     why static linking of software components into a single, unified,
     compiled binary forms a derivative work of the original components.
     As publishers of the GNU GPL and defenders of software freedom, the
     FSF has a basic ethical imperative to educate the public and the
     judiciary about the license and its terms.  The FSF respects the due
     process of law, and thus plans to continue to offer our General
     Counsel as an expert witness; Professor Moglen has donated his time
     to the MySQL legal team, as he donates his time to the Foundation,
     for the public good.  The FSF believes that the best way to serve the
     Free Software community is to educate and clear up common
     misconceptions about the GNU GPL, and will continue to do so despite
     attacks from those who oppose software freedom.
   </Para>
<BoilerPlateFooter/>
</Body>    

</PressRelease>

<!-- Local variables: -->
<!-- compile-command: "xmllint 2002-03-01-pi-MySQL.xml" -->
<!-- End: -->
