<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">

<!-- Business wire confirmation number: 1080879c -->

<PressRelease>

<FileBase>2002-08-01-sf-fundraiser</FileBase>

  <Copyright years="2002">Free Software Foundation, Inc.</Copyright>

  <License>
      Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is
      permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
  </License>

<Title>Affero Hosts "Full Tilt for Software Freedom", a Benefit for Free
  Software Foundation on Wednesday, August, 14, 2002 in San
  Francisco</Title>

  <ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>
  
  <Location>San Francisco, CA, USA</Location>

  <Date>Wednesday, August 14, 2002</Date>

  <KeyWordList>
    <KeyWord value="GNU"/>
    <KeyWord value="FSF"/>
    <KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
    <KeyWord value="Linux"/>
    <KeyWord value="freedom"/>
    <KeyWord value="software"/>
    <KeyWord value="rights"/>
  </KeyWordList>

  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
    <Name>Ravi Khanna</Name>
    <Email>pr@fsf.org</Email>
    <Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsf.org/</URL>
  </Contact>

<Body>
   <Para>
    For the benefit of FSF, Affero is hosting a party and fund-raising
    evening on Wednesday, August 14, 2002 from 6 PM to 10 PM at Club NV at
    525 Howard Street in San Francisco, CA.  We invite all, including
    attendees of the nearby LinuxWorld Conference and Expo, to participate
    in this "Full Tilt for Software Freedom", where attendees will enjoy
    an evening of vintage pinball gaming.  Free (as in price) snacks will
    be provided and a cash bar will be available.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    A $10 donation to FSF is suggested for this event.  In addition, some
    pinball tables will be sponsored by companies, including HP and IBM.
    Each table sponsor will donate $5,000 in the name of the
    highest-scoring player on the table that evening.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    The event will be highlighted by the music of Shady Lady.  In
    addition, Bradley M. Kuhn, Executive Director of FSF, and Lawrence
    Lessig, noted author and law professor at Stanford University will
    each make brief remarks about the issues of software freedom.  They
    both will be available at the event for questions and discussion with
    attendees.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    Those who would like to engage in an extensive discussion with Kuhn
    and Lessig are invited to support the FSF further by attending a
    fund-raising dinner prior to the "Full Tilt" event.  The fund-raising
    dinner will be held at a nearby restaurant, and the cost of $250 per
    person which includes dinner and wine.  Seating is limited; you can
    reserve a space by contacting Ravi Khanna at ravi@fsf.org or at
    +1-617-620-9640.
    </Para>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation">
<Para>
The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to promoting
computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute
computer programs.  FSF promotes the development and use of free (as
in freedom) software--particularly the GNU operating system and its
GNU/Linux variants--and free documentation for free software.  FSF
also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and political issues of
freedom in the use of software.  Their web site, located at
<URL>http://www.gnu.org</URL>, is an important source of information about
GNU/Linux.  They are headquartered in Boston, MA, USA.
</Para>
</About>

<About topic="Affero">
<Para>
Affero, Inc., founded in 2001, was established to empower individuals
to introduce their communities to non-profit organizations, projects
and causes.  Services combine a rating system with a commerce system.
Individuals can rate the value of contributions as well as make
donations on behalf of the efforts extended by community participants.
All funds pledged as as result of these interactions are disbursed to
beneficiaries of the volunteer's choice.  Affero endorses the 
development and use of Free Software and their web site can be found 
at http://www.affero.org.  They are headquartered in San Francisco, 
CA, USA.
</Para>
</About>


<BoilerPlateFooter/>
</Body>    

</PressRelease>

<!--  LocalWords:  Amicus amicus public's
 -->
