<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">
<!-- Business wire confirmation number is: 1166922c -->

<PressRelease>

  <FileBase>2003-02-08-award</FileBase>

  <Copyright years="2003">Free Software Foundation Free Software
      Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110, USA
  </Copyright>

  <License>
      Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is
      permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
  </License>

  <Title>Professor Lawrence Lessig Awarded the 2002 FSF 
                 Award for the Advancement of Free Software</Title>

  <ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>

  <Location>Brussels, Belgium</Location>
  <Date>Saturday, February 8, 2003</Date>

  <Description>
  </Description>

  <KeyWordList>
    <KeyWord value="GNU"/>
    <KeyWord value="FSF"/>
    <KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
    <KeyWord value="Linux"/>
    <KeyWord value="award"/>
    <KeyWord value="advancement"/>
    <KeyWord value="freedom"/>
    <KeyWord value="software"/>
    <KeyWord value="Lawrence"/>
    <KeyWord value="Larry"/>
    <KeyWord value="Lessig"/>
  </KeyWordList>

FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE

  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
    <Name>Bradley M. Kuhn</Name>
    <Email>pr@gnu.org</Email>
    <Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsf.org</URL>
  </Contact>
  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation Europe</Organization>
    <Name>Georg C. F. Greve</Name>
    <Email>greve@gnu.org</Email>
    <Phone>+49-40-23809080</Phone>
    <URL>http://www.fsfe.org</URL>
  </Contact>

<Body>
   <Para>
    The Free Software Foundation (FSF) bestowed today its fifth annual FSF
     Award for the Advancement of Free Software.  FSF President and
     founder, Richard Stallman, presented the award to Professor Lawrence
     Lessig for promoting understanding of the political dimension of free
     software, including the idea that "code is law".  Lessig has also
     promoted ideas similar to free software in other related fields.
    </Para>

   <Para>
    The award ceremony was hosted at the Free and Open Source Software
     Developers' Meeting (FOSDEM) in collaboration with the Free Software
     Foundation Europe.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    A committee of Free Software leaders selected the winner and two other
     finalists from the nominations received by the public among the
     thousands of mostly volunteer programmers worldwide who dedicate
     their time to advancing Free Software.  The selection committee
     included: Enrique A. Chaparro, Frederic Couchet, Hong Feng, Miguel de
     Icaza, Raju Mathur, Frederick Noronha, Jonas Oberg, Eric Raymond,
     Guido van Rossum, Peter Salus, Suresh Ramasubramanian, and Larry
     Wall.
   </Para>
   <Para>
    Lessig was chosen from three finalists for the award.  The other
     finalists were Bruno Haible and Theo de Raadt.
   </Para>

   <Para>
    This was the fifth award of this kind.  The prior winners were Larry
     Wall, Miguel de Icaza, Brian Paul, and Guido van Rossum.
   </Para>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation Europe">

<Para>
The Free Software Foundation Europe (FSF Europe) is a charitable
non-governmental organization dedicated to all aspects of Free Software in
Europe.  Access to software determines who may participate in a digital
society.  Therefore the freedoms to use, copy, modify and redistribute
software -- as described in the Free Software definition - allow equal
participation in the information age.  Creating awareness for these
issues, securing Free Software politically and legally, and giving people
freedom by supporting development of Free Software are central issues of
the FSF Europe, which was founded in 2001 as the European sister
organization of the Free Software Foundation.
    </Para>
<Para>
More information about the FSF Europe can be found at
http://www.fsfe.org/.
     </Para>
</About>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation">
<Para>
The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to promoting
computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute
computer programs.  The FSF promotes the development and use of Free (as
in freedom) Software - particularly the GNU operating system and its
GNU/Linux variants - and Free Documentation for Free Software.  The FSF
also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and political issues of
freedom in the use of software.  Their web site, located at
http://www.fsf.org, is an important source of information about GNU/Linux.
They are headquartered in Boston, MA, USA.
</Para>

</About>
</Body>

   <BoilerPlateFooter/>
</PressRelease>
