<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">
<!-- Business wire confirmation number is: 1182940c -->

<PressRelease>

  <FileBase>2003-03-27-patron</FileBase>

  <Copyright years="2003">Free Software Foundation Free Software
      Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110, USA
  </Copyright>

  <License>
      Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is
      permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
  </License>

  <Title>FSF Announces Corporate Patronage Program</Title>

  <ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>

  <Location>Boston, MA, USA</Location>
  <Date>Thursday, March 27, 2003</Date>

  <Description>
  </Description>

  <KeyWordList>
    <KeyWord value="GNU"/>
    <KeyWord value="FSF"/>
    <KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
    <KeyWord value="Linux"/>
    <KeyWord value="patron"/>
    <KeyWord value="sponsor"/>
    <KeyWord value="patronage"/>
    <KeyWord value="software"/>
    <KeyWord value="corporate"/>
    <KeyWord value="company"/>
    <KeyWord value="support"/>
    <KeyWord value="organization"/>
    <KeyWord value="membership"/>
  </KeyWordList>

FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE

  <Contact>
    <Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
    <Name>Ravi Khanna</Name>
    <Email>patron@fsf.org</Email>
    <Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
    <URL>http://patron.fsf.org/</URL>
  </Contact>

<Body>
   <Para>
Following the highly successful launch of its Associate Membership
program, the Free Software Foundation (FSF) announced today its new
Corporate Patronage Program.  According to FSF's Executive Director
Bradley M. Kuhn, "since its launch in late November, more than 950 people
have signed up as Associate Members of FSF.  We are now offering a similar
opportunity to the community of businesses that use Free Software."
    </Para>

   <Para>
A number of FSF's existing corporate supporters have already signed up as
part of today's launch.  They include companies of all sizes -- from
industry giants to small start-up ventures.  They include: Ada Core
Technologies, ACT/Europe, Affero, Best Practical, Brainfood, Cyclades
Corporation, HP, IBM, MySQL, OEone Corporation and Penguin Computing.
   </Para>
   <Para>
 "The freedom to create is at the core of innovation, and FSF fully embraces
this principle," said Marcio Saito, vice president of technology at Cyclades,
a data center fault management company that has built a global business on
GNU/Linux technology. "FSF is in the forefront of promoting users' freedom
to run, copy, distribute, study and change software and their work is to
be commended."
   </Para>
   <Para>
 FSF's Corporate Patrons can display the Patronage logo on their materials
and website, will be listed on FSF's Corporate Patronage website
(<URL>http://patron.fsf.org/</URL>), will receive two free hours of
consulting from FSF's GPL Compliance Lab, and will receive two
complimentary passes to FSF-sponsored seminars.
   </Para>

   <Para>
 "The FSF has been, and will continue to be, at the apex of the movement
to promote and defend free software ideals, " said Marten Mickos,
CEO of MySQL AB.  "MySQL has built a successful business on its GPL
software license, and applauds the FSF's efforts to defend the GPL against
license breaches and educate the world in the principles of free software.
We're pleased to extend our partnership with FSF as a corporate patron."
   </Para>

<Para>
 Patronage dues are on a sliding scale based on the number of employees at
a company, or at a particular division of a large company.  Regardless of
the size of the company and the dues they pay, all participating companies
will receive the same benefits.  The dues range from $500 for companies
with five or less employees to $10,000 for companies with over 10,000
employees.
</Para>

<Para>
 Organizations or companies who wish to sign up as a Corporate Patron or
 want to learn more about the Corporate Patronage Program are encouraged
 to contact FSF.
</Para>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation">
<Para>
The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to promoting
computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and redistribute
computer programs.  The FSF promotes the development and use of Free (as
in freedom) Software - particularly the GNU operating system and its
GNU/Linux variants - and Free Documentation for Free Software.  The FSF
also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and political issues of
freedom in the use of software.  Their web site, located at
http://www.fsf.org, is an important source of information about GNU/Linux.
They are headquartered in Boston, MA, USA.
</Para>

</About>
</Body>

   <BoilerPlateFooter/>
</PressRelease>

<!--  LocalWords:  KeyWord KeyWordList
 -->
<!-- &aring; <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html;
charset=iso-latin-1"> -->