<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE PressRelease SYSTEM "/home/bkuhn/Files/Projects/FSF/Volunteer-Groups/Webmasters/www/Press-Release-Tools/PressRelease.dtd">

<PressRelease>
<FileBase>2004-01-02-nyc-seminars</FileBase>
<Copyright years="2004">
Free Software Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin St, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110, USA</Copyright>
<License>
Verbatim copying and distribution of this entire article is permitted in any medium, provided this notice is preserved.
</License>
<Title>FSF To Host Free Software Licensing Seminars and Discussions on SCO v. IBM in New York</Title>
<ReleaseTime>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</ReleaseTime>
<Location>Boston, MA, USA</Location>
<Date>Friday, January 2, 2004</Date>
<KeyWordList>
<KeyWord value="GNU"/>
<KeyWord value="FSF"/>
<KeyWord value="Free Software Foundation"/>
<KeyWord value="Linux"/>
<KeyWord value="new york"/>
<KeyWord value="freedom"/>
<KeyWord value="seminar"/>
<KeyWord value="GPL"/>
<KeyWord value="SCO"/>
<KeyWord value="IBM"/>
<KeyWord value="General Public License"/>
<KeyWord value="copyright"/>
<KeyWord value="organization"/>
<KeyWord value="license"/>
</KeyWordList>
<Contact>
<Organization>Free Software Foundation</Organization>
<Name>Ravi Khanna</Name>
<Email>communication@fsf.org</Email>
<Phone>+1-617-542-5942</Phone>
<URL>http://www.fsf.org/licenses/NYC_Seminars_Jan2004.html</URL>
</Contact>

<Body>

<Para>
The Free Software Foundation (FSF) will host two seminars on Free Software
Licensing and the GNU GPL and a series of conversations with Professor
Eben Moglen on the SCO v. IBM lawsuit.  These events will take place at
Columbia Law School in New York City on January 20 and 21, 2004.

</Para>
<Para>

In the last few months, the Santa Cruz Organization Group (SCO) has been
sowing confusion and misinformation regarding the validity of the GNU
General Public License (GPL) as part of their strategy to extort money
from users of the kernel named Linux, which is licensed under FSF's GPL.
These seminars and discussions will present the facts about the license
from FSF, its creators, who authored the license in 1989.  Today, the GNU
GPL is the most popular and widely used Free Software copyright license.

</Para>
<Para>

The seminars will provide detailed study and analysis of the GPL, review
GPL enforcement cases handled by FSF's GPL Compliance Laboratory, and
consider legal ethics in Free Software Licensing.  Daniel Ravicher, Senior
Counsel to FSF, and Bradley M. Kuhn, Executive Director of FSF, will lead
the seminars.
</Para>
<Para>

The first seminar, "Detailed Study and Analysis of GPL and LGPL", held on
January 20, 2004, will give a section-by-section explanation of the GPL,
and will educate lawyers, software developers, managers and business
people on how to use the GPL (and GPL'd software) successfully in new Free
Software businesses and in existing, successful enterprises.

</Para>
<Para>

The second seminar, "GPL Compliance Case Studies and Legal Ethics in Free
Software Licensing" held on January 21, 2004, will present the details of
a few different GPL compliance cases handled by FSF's GPL Compliance
Laboratory.  Each case offers unique insights into problems that arise
when the terms of the GPL are not properly followed, and how diplomatic
negotiation between the violator and the copyright holder can yield
positive results for both parties. This seminar also includes a unit on
the ethical considerations for attorneys who want to represent clients
that make, use, or sell Free Software products.

</Para>
<Para>

FSF will also host "SCO Without Fear", a series of two
lunchtime conversations with Professor Eben Moglen, who serves on FSF's
Board and as its General Counsel.  He will discuss the SCO v. IBM lawsuit
and SCO's attacks on Free Software, and their implications for the
development and use of Free Software.  Some of Prof. Moglen's earlier
writings on the SCO v. IBM lawsuit can be found at
<URL>http://www.fsf.org/philosophy/sco/sco.html</URL>.  These
conversations will also be held on January 20-21, 2004 at Columbia
University in New York.
</Para>

<Para>

More details about these events are available at
<URL>http://www.fsf.org/licenses/NYC_Seminars_Jan2004.html</URL>.
</Para>

<About topic="Free Software Foundation">
<Para>

The Free Software Foundation, founded in 1985, is dedicated to promoting
computer users' right to use, study, copy, modify, and
redistribute computer programs.  The FSF promotes the development and use
of Free (as in freedom) Software - particularly the GNU operating system
and its GNU/Linux variants - and Free Documentation for Free Software.
The FSF also helps to spread awareness of the ethical and political issues
of freedom in the use of software.  Their web site, located at
http://www.fsf.org, is an important source of information about
GNU/Linux. They are headquartered in Boston, MA, USA.
</Para>
</About>
<About topic="Eben Moglen">
<Para>
Eben Moglen is Professor of Law and Legal History at the Columbia Law
School, where he has taught since 1987. He clerked for Judge Edward
Weinfeld of the United State District Court for the Southern District of
New York and for Justice Thurgood Marshall of the United States Supreme
Court. Before and during law school he was a designer and implementer of
advanced computer programming languages at IBM's Santa Teresa Laboratory
and Thomas J. Watson Research Center. His principal areas of interest are
Anglo American legal history, constitutional law, computers and free
expression, and intellectual property. Since 1993, he has served as pro
bono General Counsel for the Foundation and has served on its board since
July 2000.
</Para>
</About>
</Body>
<BoilerPlateFooter/>
</PressRelease>
