<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>What's New at GNU</title><link>http://www.gnu.org/whatsnew.html</link><description>What's new at the GNU project</description><copyright>(C) Free Software Foundation 2004</copyright><item><pubDate>26 January 2011</pubDate><title>A first installment of a GNU Status Repo...</title><description>A first installment of a GNU Status Report is available.  This is a partial revival of the original GNU's Bulletin, with the aim of providing GNU-wide information from time to time, for as many packages as possible.  More info.</description><link>http://www.gnu.org/bulletins/gnustatus-2011-01.html</link><pubDate>26 January 2011</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>9 December 2010</pubDate><title>Savannah was down for a few days recentl...</title><description>Savannah was down for a few days recently due to a password compromise and then a disk failure.  Also, some Apache features have been turned off for web pages.  Full news items.</description><link>http://savannah.gnu.org/news/</link><pubDate>9 December 2010</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>16 November 2010</pubDate><title>US citizens: Stop the Internet blacklist...</title><description>US citizens: Stop the Internet blacklist bill. Sign the petition at http://demandprogress.org/blacklist, and see the post on fsf.org for more information.</description><link>http://demandprogress.org/blacklist/</link><pubDate>16 November 2010</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>29 September 2010</pubDate><title>Interested in free video formats? We nee...</title><description>Interested in free video formats? We need your help! The FSF is looking for a few volunteers willing to commit an average of a few hours per week as reliable technical consultants helping people transcode their videos to free formats like WebM and Ogg Theora.</description><link>http://www.fsf.org/blogs/community/interested-in-free-video-formats-we-need-your-help</link><pubDate>29 September 2010</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>30 June 2010</pubDate><title>The June issue of the Free Software Supp...</title><description>The June issue of the Free Software Supporter is out -- you can read it and subscribe to receive future monthly issues by e-mail.</description><link>http://lists.fsf.org/archive/html/info-fsf/2010-06/msg00003.html</link><pubDate>30 June 2010</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>25 March 2010</pubDate><title>GNU urges people working on free softwar...</title><description>GNU urges people working on free software to follow standards and guidelines for universal accessibility on GNU/Linux and other free operating systems with the release of the GNU Accessibility Statement.</description><link>http://www.gnu.org/accessibility/accessibility.html</link><pubDate>25 March 2010</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>20 March 2010</pubDate><title>FSF President Richard Stallman explains ...</title><description>FSF President Richard Stallman explains the dangers of Software as a Service for free software in a new article.</description><link>http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/who-does-that-server-really-serve.html</link><pubDate>20 March 2010</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>2 January 2010</pubDate><title>All packages using GNU Automake to produ...</title><description>All packages using GNU Automake to produce distribution tarballs with make dist should update to the 1.11.1 or 1.10.3 release, or otherwise work around the problem.</description><link>http://www.gnu.org/software/automake/</link><pubDate>2 January 2010</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>31 December 2009</pubDate><title>The FSF is hosting a GNU Hackers' Meetin...</title><description>The FSF is hosting a GNU Hackers' Meeting for GNU maintainers and contributors from March 18th-21st as part of the LibrePlanet 2010 conference in Cambridge, Massachusetts. Read the details and RSVP.</description><link>http://groups.fsf.org/wiki/LibrePlanet2010/GNUHackersMeeting</link><pubDate>31 December 2009</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>23 July 2009</pubDate><title>FSF president Richard Stallman explains ...</title><description>FSF president Richard Stallman explains the unintended interactions between the Swedish Pirate Party's platform and free software -- and proposes a solution -- in his new article, How the Swedish Pirate Party Platform Backfires on Free Software.</description><link>http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/pirate-party.html</link><pubDate>23 July 2009</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>27 May 2009</pubDate><title>Help improve Canadian copyright law! The...</title><description>Help improve Canadian copyright law! The Globe and Mail has put C-61, a copyright reform bill, on a wiki for editing. See the LibrePlanet page for information on participating.</description><link>http://groups.fsf.org/wiki/Canada/RewriteCanadianCopyrightLaw</link><pubDate>27 May 2009</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>27 May 2009</pubDate><title>The FSF is hiring a new campaigns manage...</title><description>The FSF is hiring a new campaigns manager, to help with GNU and to run DefectiveByDesign, PlayOgg, and other exciting free software campaigns. Read about the job and how to apply.</description><link>http://www.fsf.org/news/campaigns-manager</link><pubDate>27 May 2009</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>7 May 2009</pubDate><title>FSF has launched a new free software act...</title><description>FSF has launched a new free software activist internship program. Applications for the summer term are due Monday, May 25. Read the full announcement.</description><link>http://fsf.org/news/new-internship-program</link><pubDate>7 May 2009</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>14 April 2009</pubDate><title>Richard Stallman has given an interview ...</title><description>Richard Stallman has given an interview to O'Reilly Media in which he talks  about Free Software licencing and a number of other current issues including  software patents, free device drivers, and the FSF's current campaigns. Read the interview here.</description><link>http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/speeches-and-interview.html</link><pubDate>14 April 2009</pubDate></item>
<item><pubDate>25 March 2009</pubDate><title>CREDIL is hosting a contest where you ca...</title><description>CREDIL is hosting a contest where you can win prize money for working on free software. It's been going for a couple of days already, but the deadline isn't until Sunday, March 28th, so there's still time. Read more.</description><link>http://www.fsf.org/blogs/community/credil-contest-2009</link><pubDate>25 March 2009</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
